https://www.foei.org/privacy-policy

Privacy policy
Friends of the Earth International is the world’s largest grassroots environmental network.
In order to campaign effectively with you, our supporters, and on your behalf, we need to collect different types of information, including personal data.
The main points in our privacy policy
We will only ever ask for what we really need to know.
We will always respect your choices around the data that you share with us and the communication channels that you ask us to use.
We will put appropriate security measures in place to protect the personal data that you share with us.
We will never sell your data.
You have the right to amend or withdraw your consent about the ways in which we hold and use your personal data at any time.
If you have any questions please contact us.
Personal data
In some areas of our website, we ask you to provide personal information that will enable us to enhance your site visit, contact you with information you request or that may be of interest to you, e.g. when you subscribe to our newsletters, make a donation, take an online action or contact us via our website. Personal information we request is limited to your name, country of residence and email address.
How is personal data used?
We will only email you information about our work where you give us your consent to do so.
We may email you information we believe may be of interest to you. For example, when you consent to being contacted by email, we might email you to take action (such as sign a petition) or make a donation. You may also receive a welcome email letting you know about other ways to support us. Emails we send you will always give you the chance to opt out of receiving further emails. Alternatively, you can contact us to unsubscribe from our emails.
Sharing personal data
Friends of the Earth International will not share your personal information with third parties unless absolutely necessary. For example if you sign a petition which involves a hand in to a government, it may be necessary to include your name on the petition hand in. These details will not be shared further. Otherwise we will only disclose your data if we are obliged to do so by law.
If you have given your specific consent for us to share your data, we may share your contact details with the Friends of the Earth group in your country of residence.
Keeping your details up to date
The accuracy of your personal information is important to us. If you change email address or name  please contact us.
We aim to amend or delete any information we hold that is incorrect within one month or as soon as possible thereafter.
Security
The security of your personal information is important to us and we will take appropriate precautions to protect it.
We use Paypal for handling donation payments. Friends of the Earth International does not have access to your payment details. Please see Paypal’s privacy policy as we are not responsible for the way Paypal handles data.
Even with all of our precautions, no data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. So, whilst we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information which you disclose to us online and you must understand that you do so at your own risk.
We take steps to ensure that access to personal information is restricted to employees who need it. All Friends of the Earth International employees who handle personal information are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices.
Use of cookies
In order to optimize our website, we use third party cookies. Cookies are small pieces of information sent by a web server to a web browser, which enable the server to collect information from the browser. Like many websites, Friends of the Earth International’s site uses cookies to provide you with a personalized web service, which includes monitoring the performance of our web pages and data on which social media platforms people access our web pages from.
Currently Friends of the Earth International’s site mainly uses third party cookies from Google, Twitter and Facebook. We sometimes use cookies to enable other areas of our site to function well, for example a cookie might be used to track whether a user has already signed a petition.
We use Google Analytics to monitor and improve our website. Google Analytics uses cookies to collect non personal information, like your IP address, your browser, your location and the pages you visit. Please check Google Analytics for details on their cookies and their policies. We only use Google analytics to analyse how users use our site, for example to find out how many people visit our site or an individual web page and from which social media platforms our visitors click through from to view our website. We do not use Google analytics information to identify visitors – all the information we access is aggregated and anonymous. And we only use this information to improve our content and our website.
We also embed content from other sites, such as social media websites or media outlets, and add buttons from social media platforms so that you can share our content. This can result in cookies being used by third parties such as Twitter and Facebook. You should check the relevant third-party website for more information about their cookies.
Cookies may be set by us or third parties. By continuing to browse our site you’re agreeing to our use of cookies. You may avoid the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. Please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of our website.
Changes
We may make changes to this Policy from time to time. If we change our Privacy Policy we will post the changes on this page and we will hold a record of changes that we make. Please revisit the policy when you want to confirm how we use your personal information. This policy was last revised on 22 May 2018
Access to your personal information
Under the General Data Protection Regulation, you have the right to request and be sent:
confirmation that your data is being processed;
access to your personal data; and
other supplementary information that we hold about you.
To make a request please contact us. We will take steps to confirm your identity before releasing any information to you. We will not charge you for providing the information that you request. We aim to amend or delete any information we hold that is incorrect within one month or as soon as possible thereafter.
Your rights and acceptance of this policy
By sharing your consent preferences, and by using our website, you consent to the collection and use of information by Friends of the Earth International in accordance with our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our site.
Privacy policy for minors
The protection of children is very important to us and we don’t actively seek opportunities to collect personal information from under-18s.  If you are under 18, please do not provide us with any personal information. Minors should always ask a parent or guardian for permission before sending personal information to anyone online.
Information retention
We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is appropriate for the activity that you are supporting (for example participating in a campaign or making a donation to support our work). If you ask for your personal information to be deleted we will manage your request in a transparent way, and in line with our data retention policy.
Email
Whilst we will take all reasonable steps to protect and secure your personal data, we cannot guarantee the confidentiality of any messages transmitted between you and us via email as these are potentially accessible by the public. We will not be liable to you or anyone else for any loss relating to any email message sent by you to us or by us to you.
All the data that we use is held in accordance with the requirements laid out in current data protection legislation. If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any questions about how we manage our data, please contact us.
WorldwideThe world's largest grassroots environmental networkSelect member groupSelect member groupCameroonGhanaLiberiaMaliMauritiusMozambiqueNigeriaSierra LeoneSouth AfricaTanzaniaTogoTunisiaUgandaAustraliaBangladeshEast TimorIndonesiaJapanKoreaMalaysiaNepalPalestinePapua New GuineaPhilippinesRussiaSri LankaAustriaBelgium (Flanders and Brussels)Belgium (Wallonia and Brussels)Bosnia and HerzegovinaBulgariaCroatiaCyprusCzech RepublicDenmarkEngland, Wales and Northern IrelandEstoniaFinlandFranceGeorgiaGermanyHungaryIrelandLatviaLithuaniaLuxembourgMacedoniaMaltaNetherlandsNorwayPolandRussiaScotlandSlovakiaSloveniaSpainSwedenSwitzerlandYoung Friends of the Earth EuropeArgentinaBrazilChileColombiaCosta RicaCuraçaoEl SalvadorGrenadaGuatemalaHaitiHondurasMexicoParaguayUruguayCanadaUnited States of America
Follow us
Facebook
TwitterTweets van @FoEintShare
Close
Enter the site
Login
Password
Remember me
Forgot password?
